AHMED **YOUSRY**

Bolack Al Dakrour (Giza)

01143722694 - 01003736147



ahmed.vousrv.shabaan2020@gmail.com



https:/www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-yousry-b13ba81a6 in



PERSONAL INFO

Software developer with main interest of web development with PHP and its related framework specially Laravel, I can handle full stack work, starting from Front-end to Back-end and it's Relational database and API's, Familiarity with the whole web stack, including front-end and back-end technologies, frameworks, libraries, and other web server optimization techniques, with experience in software engineering, problem solving and deep knowledge in OOP, solid principles, Design Patterns, I like challenges, learning new technologies and thinking and discover new ways of approaching and solving problems.

SKILLS

- Analyze website and application requirements
- Write clean, effective back-end code and build efficient modules
- Develop back-end portals with an optimized database
- Collaborate with front-end developers to integrate works into the application
- Identify areas for modification in our existing systems and make improvements
- Solve integration and incompatibility issues in our software applications
- Troubleshoot application and code issues
- Experience with APIs and popular third-party
- Proficient with one or more back-end technologies such as PHP, Java, C, Laravel, among others
- Working knowledge of DBMS such as MySQL, Oracle DB, among others
- Experience with databases and Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) frameworks
- Knowledge of coding languages, such as C++, Java, JavaScript, and code versioning tools
- Skilled at various web and mobiles technologies & their nuances like HTML, CSS, Vue, Flutter design among others



EDUCATION

PH. D | Faculty of Computers and Artificial Intelligence | Helwan University 2017 - 2021

Main Specialization: Information System (IS) Sub Specialization: Computer Science (CS)

Grade: Very Good Graduation Project: A+

Training | YAT Learning Centers

2020

Training certificate in web development from the Ministry of Communications.



EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer | On Time Group

AUG 2021 - JAN 2022

- Design, build and maintain innovative PHP(Laravel) applications
- develop new/existing software applications
- Design and maintain databases, Analyze, design, develop, as well as implement RESTful services and APIs.

Full Stack Developer | Alwasaq

DEC 2021 - PRESENT

- Backend & Frontend Web Development
- Back-end development and maintenance of websites using Laravel and MySQL
- Develop API Services
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality products
- Implement, integrate, and document a variety of software platforms through the REST API framework
- Developing advanced database driven websites & systems including E-Commerce
- collaborate with other team members such as product managers, UI/UX designers, developers, system analysts, and marketing managers to produce the desired software solutions

Freelancer |

AUG 2021 - PRESENT

- Backend & Frontend Web Development
- Develop API Services



TECHNOLOGIES

- PHP
- Laravel
- Livewire
- JavaScript
- REST API

- Vue.js
- Ajax
- Bootstrap
- воосыар
- Solid Design
 - Principles
- Design Patterns
- jQuery
- Dart
- Java
- MYSQL
- C
- GIT
- OOP
- MVC
- HTML-CSS
- Flutter



PROJECTS

HR Attendance Management System (Laravel and Flutter) | GP Project 2020 – 2021

This app is a free attendance management system helps you to manage your employees and staff attendance with the help of a simple QR code scanner by allowing the employee to check-in and check-out using QR Code from their mobile phone only and detect their Locations with GPS (location services).

The system will consist of two main components as following:

Mobile App: to be used for staff (employees) to record their attendance and absence and follow up on the date of attendance and absence in the form of reports and request permission for vacations or early departure.

Dashboard (Web App): HR system to manage all functionalities (employees and attendances, leaves, shifts, tasks, holidays, QR Code generation, etc.).

Demo: https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1SJqSlxromxIJa5Kz0Uig4OpTAkz7Ej6v

Middle East Events | Alwasaq Company Project

2022

The Middle East for Events is an online platform owned by the modern Al-Fouad institution to organize conferences and showcases in different fields. Also, Middle East platform has an advanced virtual reality for the purpose of event presentations.

Demo: https://me-events.me/ar

Admin Panel: https://me-events.me/public/ar/dashboard

DGO Tour (Backend-API Laravel and Front-End Vue js) | Freelance Project 2022

The DGO Tour application works as an electronic platform that provides the honorable tourist with prebooking the driver or tour guide, in days and hours, with the ability to choose and manage daily tours and programs before reaching the specified destination, in accordance with the following terms and conditions. The application, with its tourist services, targets individuals, families, groups, and anyone who wishes to benefit from the services of a driver and a tour guide, car rental.

The application connects the tourist, driver, and tour guide through the application. It also provides electronic payment services, canceling the reservation or changing its dates.

Demo: https://def.techno2030.com/

Admin Panel: https://de.techno2030.com/ar/login

Electro-Ecommerce (Laravel) | On Time Group Company

2021

A website that sells electronic products has:

Cart module – Orders module – Admin Dashboard – Products module – categories module – Search Autocomplete.

Demo: http://ecommerce.otgcom.com/

Admin Panel: http://ecommerce.otgcom.com/dashboard/login

BuyByShop App (Laravel) | Freelance Project

2021

Multi-vendor e-Commerce app for buying favorite stuff in clothing, electronics, foods and more. This offers a broad range of choices in various categories, sort accounts and financial reports, organize and manage products, manage customers across the globe, introduce customer-related benefits in promo codes, discounts, & coupons.

Admin Panel:

Sellers can share details of item data, shipping preparation, vendor facilities, miscellaneous activities, track orders, managing of credit data for customers and installment sales.

Notification System - SEO Plan - Payment Gateways – SMS Integration

Demo: https://buybyshop.com/

Admin Panel: https://buybyshop.com/admin/login

Agtrade Store | Alwasaq Company

2022

E-Commerce website for import & export & commercial agencies.

Demo: https://agtrade.store/

Admin Panel: https://agtrade.store/dashboard

medscript | Alwasaq Company

2022

E-Commerce website for import & export & commercial agencies.

Demo: https://medscript.madinahitech.com/

Admin Panel: https://medscript.madinahitech.com/dashboard/login

Efodia User App (Backend-API Laravel) | On Time Group Company

2021

An application booking appointments like Vezeeta with various specialties.

Efodia Owner App (Backend-API PHP) | On Time Group Company

2021

An application enables the owner to register as a specialist in a particular field has:

Info details (documents) module – Locations module – Setting module – Work hours (timecard) module – Profile (rates) module – Confirm/Waiting Requests module – Booking history reports module.

Tour Packages System (Laravel) | Personal Project

2018

"Tour Package System" is a specific web-based reservation system designed to make it easier for people to book tour packages online.

Demo: https://drive.google.com/drive/u/0/folders/1BF5-c83QMcGxHCoETi241BNx3qMymE8L

POS System (Laravel and JavaScript) | Personal Project

2020

Point of Sales System

CMS (Laravel and JavaScript) | Personal Project

2018

Content management system

Forum (Laravel and Vue.js) | Personal Project 2019

Movie DB (Vue.js and API Laravel) | Personal Project 2019

Laravel 8 CRUD-with-Livewire | Personal Project 2021